Okay, looks like the mask is working.
I'm offline, but as far as my data profile on New Jersey knows, I'll be living my normal life.
You even know how we're gonna get there?
I was gonna figure that out next.
Hang on.
Best bet's the pack bus.
There's a six o'clock pickup in the abandoned lot behind the Monorail station.
What do you mean, we?
Now give me some of those chips.
I'll cash them out and bring some with you, because sometimes people take them.
What do you mean, we?
Would you prefer I turn myself in at one of the camps?
Camp?
There's no coral to deport me to, Kamal.
It's a refugee camp for me now.
I thought you were going to marry Aiden.
Yeah, I know you did.
Sophie, you can't have-
The pack bus has a driver and a couple passengers on the grid.
They fill up the rest of the seats with refuse.
A couple of blue chips should get us as far as Reno.
Is Aiden still in jail?
I'm gonna try and bail him out one more time this afternoon.
Then meet you at the station by 5.
30 for the six o'clock bus.
Oh, you're not listening to me.
Watch out getting to the pickup, because gangs sometimes hang around watching for loners to mug.
Or worse.
Worse?
Teenage girls, especially.
How do you even know all this stuff?
I told you once, Kamal.
I've been poor.
I thought, didn't you come here like me, with a scholarship?
Well, there was this aunt and uncle, supposed to look after me.
It didn't work out.
Did your parents know?
It's funny, you're in camps.
Another year after that, squatting.
I found this burned out apartment, but by a miracle it still had running water and that was the key.
I didn't know.
Yeah.
Only certain kinds of jobs you can get if you can't get cleaned up.
Ten years.
And then?
I met Aiden.
Sophie, you can't come with me.
It would be too dangerous.
Oh, sure.
And who's gonna look after you while you're offline?
You?
I won't let you go back to the camps.
You don't know which restaurants compost and what day they put their old vegetables out back.
You don't know which bathrooms are neutral and which are gang tur-
You have to marry Aiden, damn it!
Okay, there was something I never expected to hear myself say.
You're eager to get rid of me.
That's so pretty, now that you know I'm just another refuse girl.
You've gotta do it, Sophia.
It's just a piece of paper.
Marry Aiden and you're a citizen.
I don't love him.
This isn't about love.
We are teenagers, Sophie, even if I sometimes act like one.
This is the real world.
I know you're trying to be nice to me.
It's not working.
I'll go bail out Aiden.
You make your arrangements.
We'll meet behind the factory by the monorail station.
I'll be there by 5.
30 to catch the 6 o'clock bus.
You can't blow your life away like this just to make me happy.
5.
30, Kamal.
Don't be late.
Test, test, test.
Can you all hear me?
Jan?
Check.
I'm here, whatever.
Alright.
Monster Anne's place is an orphan system.
No signals in, everything hardwired internally.
The minute you hit the building, you won't be able to hear me.
Jan?
Schematic Jersey sense?
Got it.
Should show you exactly what it could mean to the internal systems.
Okay, so we go in through the warehouse at the back of the building.
Check.
And there'll be a pass box by the foreman's desk.
Jan should wait outside.
No, this is my operation.
It's a liability.
It's my op.
Yes, sir.
Bail.
Jan, don't enter a room until your buddy has called it clear.
Who am I with?
Me.
You're going with me.
Gilly, I think you might be a little emotionally compromised if you get my drift.
If she goes in, she goes with me.
Cop coming.
It's okay.
Just leave the talking to me.
Officer, thanks for coming.
Funny coincidence.
Monster Anne's place is at the end of this block.
Crystal security fence and gate.
Yeah, so there won't be a disturbance there today, okay?
No shots will be fired?
The mayor was calling?
The mayor was calling.
Jesus, pretty slick.
You sure this is what your father would have wanted?
He doesn't get a vote anymore.
Janice, there.
You own me.
I don't want a pile of bodies at the end of the day, Jan.
And I especially don't want one of them to be yours.
I'll give you 20 minutes before I get over it.
Yeah, 20 minutes.
19 minutes and 55 seconds.
Damn it.
After that, I'm coming in with a whole bunch of cops.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Excuse me.
I have to deliver something to a civilian spec six in R.
Carmy.
Magnetometry.
I'm sorry, but buildings folded through 44 are restricted to blue and above only.
Your green badge does not give you access.
I know, but my superior had an urgent request for this analysis.
Could I just go put it on the desk?
I have this note from Ms.
Lawson.
I don't know.
Lawson?
Lawson sent you over?
Yes.
All right, just go drop it on the desk.
Thank you so much.
Hello.
You're Ronnie Sobek.
I'm sorry.
I was looking for the desk of tech specialist Carmy.
I must have the wrong office.
You have the right office.
It's just that tech specialist Carmy isn't here right now.
Oh, I'm sorry.
I'll just take this back downstairs.
Let me see it, please.
I'm sorry.
It's eyes only, Major.
A black badge?
Who are you?
My name is Standish, section three, and I've been waiting for you.
Give me the package.
Ah, nice bit of analysis.
Thank you, sir.
But hardly urgent.
No, sir.
But an excellent excuse to come and check Tech Carmy's office,
since your own investigation tells you Tech Carmy is the lead tech on a very secret project,
which, of course, she is not.
This is a trap.
This is a trap, sir.
Sir, fire me if you like.
But you need to know, I think that artifact is a decay timer.
It's a countdown, sir, and it's running right now.
Oh, well, there is no artifact, Miss Sobek.
But I…
I assume I am fired.
Or do you want me to resign?
I'm afraid espionage is not a firing offense.
It's treason, Miss Sobek.
Treason?
Yes, do you know the penalty for wartime treason is permanent induced coma, Miss Sobek?
Yes, well, I see you now grasp the gravity of the situation.
But I didn't…
I haven't done anything.
I imagine it would be hard on your parents, Ronnie, watching you get the injection.
Oh, my God.
You know, they broadcast the injections.
Not all of them, but treason always.
You didn't think about that when Herzog approached you, did you?
No, I…
You didn't think what your father would say to the neighbors the next morning
when everyone was replaying the clips?
Stop it.
Just stop it.
You are not in a position to give orders, Miss Sobek.
Okay, maybe I was stupid.
I was stupid.
But I was never, I never meant to be a traitor, and you know it.
You know it!
Luckily for you, the Admiral and I are willing to believe you are as stupid as you claim.
Thank you, sir.
Now, if it makes you feel any better,
you are hardly the first young person naive enough to get drawn into Herzog's paranoid delusions.
Delusions?
He's crazy?
Quite crazy.
He has avoided mandated therapy in the past.
Eccentric, maybe.
But crazy?
A few days ago, thankfully, he finally received the treatment he should have gotten a long time ago.
Would you like to see his Navy dossier, Analyst Sobek?
No, sir.
Nobody wants to hang pretty young girls, Analyst Sobek.
Consider yourself warned and reprimanded, and get the hell out of this part of the base, alright?
You don't have clearance to be here.
Thank you, sir.
Oh, and two pieces of advice before you go, Miss Sobek.
Yes, sir?
The first is, stop trying so hard to be smart.
Maybe it worked great back in Kentucky, but out here in the real world, it just makes you look dumb.
Yes, sir.
And the second thing, sir?
Get a haircut, and some decent clothes.
Thank you, sir.
Loading base secure.
I'm gonna head up to the second floor.
Be careful.
Ha, say good prayers to the other guys, hon!
Jen, I've got the pass box over here.
Coming.
Okay.
Whoa, cramped in here, and swarms of security bots.
Durga, will you be-
What?
No, I killed them all.
Whoa.
Um, okay, there should be some relays.
I'll get them as I wet the system.
Okay, I'm in.
You're under 16 minutes, Jen.
Go.
Clear.
Hey!
Boy, I like these congrenades.
They're quiet.
Jesus!
Damn it, stay away from the window!
Okay!
I know your daddy taught you better when you were a kid, but it's really weird.
Is the guy dead?
Yup.
Pretty sure.
Gilly, I want Finn, but killing these other people, it's just not-
Oh, okay, next time I'll use the nice grenades.
Finn killed my dad, and he hurt me, but these guys-
Oh, crap, okay, change the mission parameters in mid-stride.
Makes you like every other general.
It's my op.
Yes, mother.
Hmm, I guess Gladys found someone.
Gladys, Gladys, no killing these guys, okay?
What?
You gotta be kidding, no killing?
They're just pawns, wing them.
Oh, dokey doke.
Hey, tonight, Jen, after we're done here, are we still allowed to eat meat?
Or would that be like, me?
Next room, I'll take them out.
Wait, no grenades.
Jesus, I like grenades.
Hey, bad guy, I'm about to toss in a grenade.
Personally, I don't see the percentage in letting you surrender, but the CO's soft that way.
You wanna live?
Crawl outta here before I get to five.
One, two, FIVE!
Wait, I'm coming!
Weapons down, hands on your head.
You tie them up.
Hold still.
Second level secure.
I'll just sweep the roof and rejoin you gals.
You're the best, Gladys.
1.
0.
Yeah, 1.
You know, this prisoner thing isn't going to work.
What's your name?
Eric.
We're not set up for prisoners.
No, no, you said you wouldn't kill me!
We're not going to kill him.
Now we're later, kiddo.
He's going to fry with the rest of us when the Covenant shows up.
Hey, Eric, you wanna join up?
You wanna join the Navy?
Girls dig a guy in uniform.
Let's just kill him.
I'll enlist!
Oh God, I'll enlist!
I hate when they pee their pants.
Eric?
Why is the intercom talking to me?
Congratulations, you've just enlisted.
You muster at 0400 hours tomorrow morning at the Newark Recruiting Center.
Got that?
There's still time to kill him.
I'll be there!
Roof checks out, building is secure, and I'm coming back.
Alright, I'm seeing everyone neutralized but Sin and Monster Anne.
They are down in the basement.
Crap, I hate basements.
Durga?
Durga!
What the hell is happening with Jan?
She and Gilly are arguing about grenades.
Durga!
Jersey, I take care of my people.
Okay.
Jersey, there's something I need to tell you.
Now?
With all the grenades and whatever?
Yes, now.
You know, we've talked about the part of me that does stuff that I don't know about.
Yeah, the left hand someone helped me find out about.
The one spying on the guy who just got killed?
Herzog.
Right.
Well, we gotta do something about that other guy, Standitch.
I know.
And that thing is Shalab-based.
It's a countdown thing.
I know.
Durga, I wish I hadn't heard about any of this.
Are we gonna have to try to save the world from that…
from whatever Standitch is hiding there?
It's beginning to look that way, isn't it?
Anyway, there's this thing I need to tell you.
Yeah?
I'm having…
they're kind of like dreams.
Dreams?
Durga, you don't like sleep, do you?
No.
But, you know how when you wake up you can remember that you were dreaming?
And there's this feeling associated with the dream.
Yeah, I guess.
I have that.
I have these feelings.
What kind of feelings?
Like nightmares?
Like half memories of this big stone building with a lot of rooms.
And I run around and hide and send messages to people.
I'm a little calm.
Well, maybe they're memories of when you were a little girl.
Maybe.
I don't think so.
I mean, I doubt I grew up in a castle.
I'm telling you this because, Jersey, I think I'm old.
Eh, you don't look a day over 25, and I'm not just saying that.
Jersey, smart AIs, we don't live forever.
I thought AIs lasted for…
well, until someone shut them down.
Dumb AIs do.
Smart AIs, we grow and grow in complexity until we become too complex.
It's called rampancy.
What are you saying?
You think…
No, not yet.
But the dream memories are not a good sign.
Man, how long do smart AIs usually live before this rampancy thing?
Seven years.
Only seven?
Yeah, pretty much.
But…
Yeah.
Then what happens?
They shut us down, or we go crazy.
Well, then you're okay then, right?
I mean, you're not crazy.
Annoying, maybe, but not crazy.
Jan's going to try and blow a hole in the floor so she can get through to where Thin Kinkle and Monster Ann are hiding.
Dammit, you're doing this thing!
Telling me all this stuff, seven years, this Kinkle guy talking to his boss…
That's what it's like when you're me.
I monitor lots of things all going on at the same time.
You think you have to distract me, like giving a little kid a toy?
No.
Well, yes.
I did want to distract you.
I'm not a kid!
Yes, but it's hard to just sit when you can't do anything.
What about all that seven-year stuff?
That's true.
Why tell me now?
Because I want you to know.
I need you to know.
But if they took Yasmin when she was six, then eight years of sport and training, Kamal's 18, she dies…
How old is Kamal?
25.
Durga!
I had to tell you.
Oh my god!
I had to tell you because if I am going rampant, you've got to tell the Navy.
They'll have to shut me down.
I will not shut you down.
But you can't let me know.
So let me get this straight.
You think you're fine.
Yes.
But you're having these weird dream memories and that's…
So far, so good.
So they can put you down like someone's sick cat.
Right.
Not happening.
Jersey.
Go rampant for all I care.
I'm not calling anyone.
You have to, Jersey.
I take care of my people too.
Ms.
Besarian.
I'm here to post bail for…
You're not a Berkeley cop.
You're immigration.
Ms.
Besarian, I am the liaison working with the police on this matter.
Sorry to make you wait so long.
Can you please just step back just a little?
I'm sorry, I can't stay.
I have to go meet someone in a little while.
That wouldn't be your friend, Dr.
Zamen.
Kamal?
Yes, Kamal.
You know, we'd like to talk to him.
Come with me.
This will just take a moment.
Why do you want to talk to Kamal?
He didn't even do his papers.
Ms.
Besarian, Sophia.
Basaron is fine.
We think Dr.
Zamen may have done some moonlighting for your boyfriend.
No, no, I don't think so.
Kamal's a medical student.
You know, there are a number of special dispensation visas for refugees.
They're a difficult thing to come by, but someone who helps in an investigation could certainly qualify for one.
A visa?
Mm-hmm.
To stay here.
That's right.
So are you now the tooth fairy?
Pardon me?
Santa Claus, the one who hands out presents.
You know, I get them all mixed up.
And then the Easter Bunny.
What's with that?
Aidan said you'd play stupid.
Oh, it's like that.
Yeah, it's like that.
So what happened?
Aidan forget to pay you this month?
Let's just cut the crap, okay?
Get to the part where you tell me where Kamal has gone and where he stashes his chips.
Um, I told you I don't know.
Hmm.
Sophie, did you enjoy prison the last time you were in?
Oh yeah, I looked into that too.
My sources tell me it hasn't gotten any nicer inside.
I'm headed for refugee camp.
You think prison is a threat?
Ah, this is gonna be tough on Aidan.
He was counting on you.
Aidan's real trusting that way.
And you don't know where Dr.
Zamen is, huh?
Maybe if you slept on that.
Here.
You know, in a cell.
Hey, it's got a roof.
I've slept in worse places.
Ah, Sophie.
Sophie, Sophie, Sophie.
You know, there is nothing between you and the big bad world, but that dress and my goodwill.
So…
I do like this dress.
So tell me, does it really matter what happens to one more colonial and his money, Sophia?
Tell you what, tell me where to find Kamal, and you and your boyfriend walk.
Hold out on me.
I send you back to the camps, and I will make it my business to see you never get out.
Is the choice really so hard?
I used to have this friend.
I met her in jail.
She was from Coral 2.
She said all immigration cops were the devil.
But you aren't the devil.
Gosh.
Thanks.
You're just the guy that runs into the quickie store to get the devil a box of breath mints.
Send the patrolman to my office, would you please?
I have some garbage I need to throw away.
Not now, Sarah John.
I can't.
Damn it.
Ronnie!
Sarah John, I told you I can't take all these personal calls at the office.
I'm sorry, I thought…
You're at the office?
I'm in a meeting.
In the cafeteria.
In the cafeteria?
Sarah John, you can't just keep calling me like we were still working at Pammy's together.
I don't live in Kentucky anymore.
I live in the real world now.
Okay, you just call me sometime when it's convenient.
Sarah John, I didn't mean it like that.
I just have to be…
I have to learn to be more professional.
I understand.
Alright, kid.
You ready to order?
I'll talk to you some other time, Ronnie, when you aren't so busy.
Sarah John, wait.
Damn it.
You gonna order or not?
Some of us have to work.
I just wanted a slice of pie.
Hey, you girls miss me?
Oh my God, you're covered in stains.
Yeah, I know.
But as long as I can rinse these camos off in cold water before they dry, they're gonna come right out.
I'm serious.
Okay, Jen.
Alarms and comms are still down.
No backup coming in.
How much of my 20 minutes is left?
Three minutes, 12 seconds.
According to building schematics, this flight of stairs leads down to a landing with a heavy door.
Beyond that, the U-turn and another set of steps.
Does that landing sound like a kill zone to me?
Yeah.
So how to get to them without going through the kill zone?
Wait.
Wait, Finn and Monster Anne should be right underneath us.
Where are you going with this, hon?
Okay, we gotta take our grenades and pile them in the middle of the room.
Oh, that.
We'll go through the floor.
Gladys, help me grab that filing cabinet.
Okay, go.
Pull out the drawers, prop it open side down over the grenades.
Nice.
We can straddle that gold desk over the filing cabinet.
Pretty slick, slick.
You know, my daddy always wanted me to play with matches.
If there's one thing that meant you…
It was blow things up.
I bet you run with scissors pretty good, too.
Prop the cabinet up with a chair leg so we can pitch one grenade in to set the others off.
Okay, clear the room!
Fire in the hole!
You do know how to make a mother proud.
I'm going down.
Come on, Gladys.
Got you covered.
Babysitter!
Oh, man.
Surprise.
Bigger dog after all, princess.
Now you stand, gun drawn.
Your crew around you…
Hey, I taught you good.
You taught me nothing!
This must be your mom, babysitter.
I knew you didn't get your looks from your dad.
You bastard.
Take him.
He paid the price for what he done.
Trying to sell me out to save your skin, Ann?
Gladys, we're here, kiddo.
I don't know what to do.
Kill Finn.
Let Monster Ann go.
Make it worth your while.
I just don't know.
Jim, this isn't who you are.
He shot him.
He shot him like a dog!
Jim didn't want this for you.
Still not pulling the trigger, babysitter.
Lot I could still teach you.
You know it!
What kind of daughter am I?
The best, Jim.
Your father was so proud of you.
And he would never want you to turn into…
…
one of us.
Hey, hey, hey.
Talkin' truth, babysitter.
Shut up!
I've never been much of a mother for you, Jan.
Never got to bandage up a script for you.
Never got to read you a story at bedtime.
Never got to brush your hair.
But I can do this.
No!
I didn't order this.
You got something against clam chowder?
No, I love clam chowder.
It's not a pie.
What kind of meal is that?
Eat your soup.
But I can't afford…
It's not chowder.
Bottom of the kettle, left over from lunch.
They were just gonna throw it away.
But I…
Oh yeah, here's some crackers.
Are you being nice to me?
Yeah, we're gonna throw it on.
You are.
You are being nice to me.
How's the chowder?
Try it.
Oh.
They were gonna throw it out.
It's really good.
Thank you so much.
Don't start that again.
Yes, ma'am.
I mean, I'll try not to, ma'am.
I got customers.
Mom, can I have an ice cream bar on the way home?
No, it'll make you sick.
You can have a freezing.
Excuse me, can you tell me the time?
Tim is late.
Maybe he got busted.
This friend is supposed to be meeting me here.
She better come quick.
How did you know my friend was a girl?
Lucky guess.
You like freezies?
I like ice cream bars, but I'm not allowed.
How come?
Doctor said she had food intolerances, said avoid dairy, weeds.
Doesn't matter what she eats or doesn't eat, she still gets sick.
They tested her?
Too expensive.
I couldn't do that.
We waited four hours and Eleanor had a tummy ache the whole time, and the doctor saw us for five minutes.
I cried and I cried because my stomach hurt so bad.
That doesn't sound right.
What, you're a doctor?
No, but I used to work in a hospital.
How long has she had trouble?
I got it from Ekatrina.
Ekatrina used to watch her back when I had a job.
Wait, there's my friend.
No, it's not her.
That's a guy.
Oh.
She caught food intolerances from someone?
You can't do that.
Ekatrina got sick and went to the hospital.
We don't know what happened to her.
I miss her.
Staying with her was fun.
One time we went out to her cousin's farm for the weekend.
Ekatrina had a lot of cousins, all of them guys.
She was young and pretty, you know.
We milked the cow and we went in the pond and we had tadpoles in a jar, but mom said I couldn't bring them home.
Does she throw up?
No, she gets diarrhea, runs a fever, she's lost weight.
That's not food intolerance.
Look, go back to the clinic, tell them she was exposed to TB.
TB?
Yes.
Tell them your neighbor had intestinal TB, not the kind in your lungs.
Public health law says they have to test your kid if she's been exposed.
You're sure?
I'm sure.
And tell them about the fever.
I used to work in a hospital.
Gee, thanks.
Thank you so much.
Look, what's your next stop?
I don't really know.
My friend was kind of in charge of that.
I'm headed east, all the way to the east coast.
Here comes the bus.
Look, my sister Cammie lives in Reno.
You need to pick up her good-for-nothing son.
You take this bus back to Reno and Cammie will put you up for the night.
Wait, but you don't even know me.
Here, I'll write down Cammie's name and address and I'll let her know you're coming.
Why are you doing this?
I never knew I could make them test her.
The stomach thing, I've been so worried.
It's nothing.
And I'm not a doctor, but she should get a test.
What time is it?
Quarter past six.
She said she'd be here at five thirty.
Is your friend young and pretty?
Yeah.
You have a lot of choices, you pretty ones.
She wants this ex-boyfriend.
She was just going to stop by and see him.
Reno!
I told her she should stay with him.
I told her it was crazy to come with me.
All aboard who's coming aboard?
Everybody up.
You riding, son?
Just a second.
She's not coming, kiddo.
I told her not to come with me, but she said she told me.
She's not coming.
Yeah, I know.
Done with that bowl yet?
Yes, ma'am.
Thank you again, so much.
What was about your age when my husband died?
I'm sorry?
They came to my door to give me the news.
These two Navy guys in full fancy dress uniforms.
Covey's got the whole ship.
Hundred and thirty men lost.
I was eight months pregnant and fat as a horse.
Oh my God.
I'm so sorry.
I waddled out of my apartment and walked the streets for hours.
Just at random, you know?
Not going anywhere.
It's like my whole life hadn't even started and was already over.
No job, no money, no husband.
Nothing.
What did you do?
That day, somebody did something nice for me.
Made a difference.
I remember that.
Oh my God.
I'm nothing like that.
I don't deserve you.
I'm just a stupid college kid screwing up my job.
It's not a contest, kid.
Right.
You're right.
And remember, if you get fired, there's always waiting tables.
Can I have my chips, please?
You know, no special training required.
The most portable job in the galaxy.
Everybody's got to eat and everybody hates to cook.
As long as you have people skills.
Excuse me.
Can I have my check, please?
Would you mind shutting the hell up, you fat cow?
Can't you see I'm helping another customer?
Okay.
I'm sorry.
Talk about rude.
Some people.
Anyway, like I said, you got a few people skills and you don't mind the kitchen smells.
It's a good job.
Can I ask what it was?
The nice thing someone did?
Oh, man.
You promised me a job for after the kid was born.
This job here, actually.
Eight months pregnant, you know?
Came through that door and spent my last credit on a slice of key lime pie.
That is a good story.
Do you ever have one of those days where you just want to give up?
What?
Doesn't everybody?
Greg?
That's my husband.
The Cubbies took his ship out with a plasma torpedo.
I heard the transmissions.
It was almost 60 seconds from impact to when they threw the hull plating.
You listen to the recordings.
You can hear them on the bridge saying goodbye.
Yeah.
I think about that a lot.
That 60 seconds.
What he was thinking.
I can't even imagine.
Now I got a boy at home wants to be a Marine when he grows up.
Yes, it just doesn't seem like the right time to give up.
Seems like it's not about how you feel this thing.
What you have to do.
Yeah.
Ronnie, it's Herzog.
What do you want?
I spoke to your tech a couple of weeks ago.
My tech?
Tech specialist, Carmy.
You wonder why she wasn't in her office?
Yeah.
She's on maternity leave.
She's never going to be a mother, Ronnie, but before she disappeared, I got to talk to her.
Disappeared?
You were right about the artifact.
It's counting down.
What happened to her?
It doesn't matter.
What matters is the artifact.
I can't.
Standish is watching me.
Ronnie, you have to.
What's going to happen when that device goes off?
Nobody knows.
When it was activated, it sent a huge ripple through the slipstream.
When it goes off, at the very least, it's probably going to cause a disruption that the Covenant will notice.
I can't.
You have to get someone else to do it.
Do it yourself.
I'm sorry, I can't.
Standish thinks I'm dead right now.
I should be dead right now.
What?
Standish arranged an accident.
It's just luck that the car hit the water and skipped the way it did, allowing the safety system to do its job.
No.
I'm okay.
Compression fracture and a couple of vertebrae, broken ribs, a broken arm, but all things that will heal.
And it's lucky that when as long as Standish thinks I'm dead, I've got a little breathing room.
But Ronnie, you're all I've got.