Okay, here come your card counters.
Phil, Cassie, Molly…
She's cute.
…
Zack, and your ringleader Antonio.
Show him the thing.
Okay.
I've wormed into their private CP channel and built an audio mask out of the voice archive samples you gave me.
Then I wrapped it around a zero lag sequencer that jacks into the…
Jesus, just show me the thing already.
I talk to…
Hi, Antonio.
Holy crap.
See Mr.
F?
Okay, I'm going to slip into their chatter line now.
I'll send a feed directly to your chatter.
You'll hear exactly what Antonio's gang is hearing.
Cassie, your deck is light on face cards.
Set your count at negative seven and hit on anything up to sixteen.
Got it.
Molly, you're a three.
Phil, you're a negative five.
You love this, don't you?
He's the hell out of competing with every bookwarming refugee from the Glass Wars for a real job, don't it?
But, did the Colonial say to the garbage books?
Put me down!
Excuse me?
Oh, sorry.
No, just remembering a joke I heard.
Hit me, please.
Alright.
Zach, the other's looking strong on your hand.
Get out.
Molly, whoa, you're up at nine now.
Bet three quarters of the table max on the next hand.
Now that Colonial crap just isn't right.
These kids go to a good school and everything.
They're just saying what everybody thinks.
We're, you know, book smart hicks and grade grabbers who act like if you fail one crummy course.
You might lose your student visa and get sent home to die.
Pull up the house record of the decks.
Okay, this is what Antonio's looking at when he tells the others how to bet.
It bothers you, though.
Not really.
I've heard it all before.
One thing makes me want to face peel a guy.
It's intolerance.
Antonio's way over by the slot machines, looking real innocent and out of sight of the others.
Now we send him for a little time out?
Yeah.
Paolo, take him to the unwelcome visitors' lounge.
Frank, fresh decks on two, four and five.
Use the ones I gave you.
Okay, the show's on monitor six.
Watch what Paolo does to this son of a bitch.
Jesus Christ, if they hit him again, I'm walking.
What, you feel sorry for this guy?
I'm done.
Fine, fine.
Have it your way.
Paolo, treat Mr.
Antonio real nice.
I don't know.
Buy him something with an umbrella in it.
Use your initiative.
You promised me nobody would get hurt if…
Don't let that thing come out.
I'm going live in three, two…
Molly, that last card puts you way positive.
Time to double down.
Zach, bet the minimum.
Dealer's about to beat you.
Phil, hash out, head to table five and get in on the next hand.
At the 10K table.
If you were seen when I'm seen, you'd already be there.
So, Dad, where are we going?
How long was this gonna take?
Dad?
Remember you wanted to meet some more of my old buddies?
Like Gladys?
Nobody's like Gladys.
When they cancelled the program, they broke us up.
Us?
Spartans.
Spartan One.
Sure, Dad.
You were an elite commando with metal bones and a flamethrower attachment that the Marines dropped in when the Tac Nukes weren't enough.
Not paranoid mythology.
A real Spartan.
They were real ones?
We were real.
We were all volunteers.
The 1.
0s.
These things they call Spartans now.
It's different?
There's a new program.
We went through some tweaks, but it's still just me in here.
The twos.
Now.
The twos aren't even human anymore.
But you are.
All too much.
Wait a sec.
You know you don't have to make up cool stuff to impress me, right?
Like, I'm not gonna suddenly start cleaning my room more often, because I think you were a super soldier with a secret pad.
I never, ever thought you would clean your room more often.
Spartans pick their battles.
You're not trying to bond with me here, are you?
When the news came yesterday.
About Reach?
That's where they brought us.
That's where they made us.
Section 3 compound.
Do you still have friends there?
Not anymore.
The work, the tests, and what they did to us in the lab.
The thing you taught me about how to beat the quiz.
That's a Spartan thing, isn't it?
The ones who made it through.
We were family.
We were tighter than family.
Is this a trip some kind of Spartan thing?
No.
One of my old buddies isn't doing so good.
Hmm.
I get to meet another one of your super friends.
Jan, I…
Oh, hey.
Did I get injections when I was a baby?
I guess you noticed you're not a typical kid.
Well, I do have excellent table manners.
Superior muscle density.
Lung capacity.
Some eye work.
Bounce?
Cogglutinin.
And when the cops took me in, they did tests.
Right.
And that would have turned out right.
So you…
Much.
So what's even me?
I mean, what's not just Spartan one voodoo potion?
Well, those table manners, for one.
Dad.
The way you roll your eyes at me, how you hate doing dishes.
Dad!
That's all you, honey.
Hell, if I'd known, I would have told the medic to skip all that fancy stuff and just cut me a nice kid.
Oh, nice.
You didn't want a nice kid.
He wanted a kid who would happily learn 23 ways to kill a man armed only with a stick of chewing gum.
You don't really think that, do you?
I'm your dream child, Dad.
Don't kid yourself.
Okay.
We're here.
Now you wait in the car.
Hey, Ronnie, where are you?
In a rental car an hour out of Dogtown.
Oh, thanks for coming.
I was kind of worried that, well, it was a new job and the boss and then I…
That I missed the wedding?
Sarah and John, I wouldn't have taken the job if I couldn't be your old maid.
You're either lying or stupid.
I'll plead the fifth.
Oh, I got the gown.
We're just checking the final fit.
Oh, what color is it?
It'll start out white and then during the reception…
Liar, liar, pants on fire.
…
you'll suffer the next day when we come pale, pale, pale a tint of pink and then slowly it'll darken until deep, gorgeous rose.
Oh, honey, it sounds gorgeous.
You hate it.
You think it sounds cheap?
No, I don't.
Oh, hell, hold on.
My boss is calling.
Ronnie, I was looking over my monthly reports.
Where are you?
I'm in Kentucky for my cousin's wedding.
I put the request in your inbox like you said.
Oh, right.
What was that?
A cow, ma'am.
Crossing the road, ma'am.
Oh, sounds mean.
They are bigger before they cut them up and put them into packages.
Ma'am, I did track down that call.
Which call?
The man from Troy who wanted to know if we had his family papers.
Doesn't exist.
Call was a fraud.
Good work, Ronnie.
Ma'am, what were the Marines doing on Troy?
Well, Ronnie, there's a war on…
Oh, but they were evacuating Troy before it fell like they knew it was going to be attacked.
There was no evacuation of Troy.
It must be some error.
But good work on that print call and give that report to me on Monday.
That is weird.
What was waiting?
My boss.
Anyway, the dress sounds beautiful.
And besides, you're the prettiest girl in town.
Under that is so not true.
If it was, I'd have been prom queen or something.
You know, Leona Philpott was a very special case.
If you'd broken your neck diving into a pool and were in a wheelchair bravely undergoing spinal column regeneration…
That's all I had to do to be homecoming queen.
Better to light a candle than curse your darkness, Sarah John.
A little initiative.
I gotta go.
Now you drive straight to the church for the rehearsal dinner, okay?
And then we'll fit your old maid of honor dress.
I can't wait.
See you.
I'm married.
You should tell her.
I couldn't do that to Sarah John.
Better call her off now than start Tomcatting around.
She's already got names picked up for our kids.
Caleb, Tamara, and Erin Marie.
Caleb?
Excuse me?
Ronnie.
Oh, God.
I didn't mean to…
I didn't hear you come in.
You leave Sarah John at the altar, Jason Gatlinburg Pope, and I'll tell your mother what you and Dale really did last year in New Orleans.
And Sarah John too.
Ronnie.
Marion Hayes.
And if you don't mind, this conversation didn't include you.
Ronnie, I…
I was…
Anything that hurts my cousin involves me, thank you.
Ronnie, this is my friend Nick.
I don't care for your choice of friends, Jason.
Nick, this is Sarah John's cousin, Ronnie.
It's his choice of wives that's the issue here.
That is none of your damn business.
From Boston.
You marry now, you leave her later.
Who does that help?
Oh, Jason isn't gonna leave her.
That sure is a nice dress, Ronnie.
Jason's gonna be a good boy.
Oh man, there's your southern girl, Jason.
Nick, please, I don't want to get Ronnie all riled up.
Too late.
Boston, interfering.
I think I hear my mom calling.
Self-righteous no-one.
Who the hell?
It's all my favorite people.
Oh, hi Sarah John.
What are you doing?
Coming up the stairs with you.
I thought I told you to stay in the car.
You did.
So I expected you to stay there.
You did?
Hmm.
Jen.
Yes, Dad?
Okay, Gilly's in number six.
Jen.
Yeah?
We're gonna want to knock maybe from off to one side of the door.
Gilly.
You there?
Jim?
This the girl?
Hey, Gilly.
You all right?
She's pretty.
Come into the kitchen.
Whoa, quite a stockpile.
I picked up a hand cannon from a guy who needed some quick cash.
I quickly bet Benny's to work.
Come on, Gilly.
I got the gauge and I thought, okay, that's good in type, but it won't give me squat at range.
And so I went looking for an SRS.
Gilly.
Then it didn't make sense not to have a good all purpose.
You don't need any.
I still feel better when I've got a pop gun around.
The grenades?
The girl's got to accessorize, Jim.
I never understand.
The M6B was a throw in on one of the other deals.
I can't remember which one.
She's prettier than I expected.
Some of those early pictures weren't too promising.
They're in good shape.
Pictures?
I've been cleaning them.
Plus, I haven't been sleeping so good.
How many days, Gilly?
Couple.
A couple.
Five.
It's time to go back, Gilly.
I don't want to go back to pasture, Jim.
What pictures?
I thought I could make it.
Out here, you know.
Most of the time I can.
Except?
Then I catch myself watching people.
I know.
That way.
Maybe a guy in the grocery store, he'll be reaching up for a box of powdered milk.
And you'll see?
Maybe a can opener on the next shelf.
One of the punch kinds.
And you're already thinking where to put him afterwards.
And yesterday.
We heard the news from Reach.
Yeah.
There's some memories about that.
So anyway, I heard about it in the store.
People talking.
Then on my way home, this kid was fixing his bike.
Gilly, it's okay.
I had the chain in my hands, Jim.
Standing behind him.
I could see all the little hairs in the back of his neck.
And I could feel the little bumps it was going to leave.
Jesus.
And it felt great.
It felt great.
But you didn't.
No.
I spent hours washing the chain oil off my hands.
Hours and hours.
You need help.
You think?
Didn't you and Jason have your first kiss right here in this room?
Mm-hmm.
Mama was cooking dinner downstairs.
And still remember…
Hold still.
Oh, God.
I'm so sick of this dress and this wedding.
We should have eloped.
Well, there's still an hour.
So, what did you think of Nick?
How much I'd like to see him sucked into a combine.
What?
Why?
He was provoking me.
I was sure you'd hit it off.
That's why I paired him with a guy who was a little bit of a jerk.
He cleared you two up.
You what?
Ow!
Watch your pins.
Well, hold still then.
Oh, God.
I just want people to have a good time.
Oh, damn it.
Ronnie!
I'm sorry.
Oh, hi, Ms.
Lawson.
You're working late.
Hmm.
Just clearing up some paperwork.
Ronnie, you just got a priority message from Fleet.
A response to a query you sent from this office to a Marine Lance Corporal Gopi.
A message?
Can you forward it?
What is this about, Ronnie?
He was on Troy during the evac.
There was no evacuation of Troy.
Millions died.
Oh, but there was an evac.
Not of everyone, but remember the guy with the family papers?
He was a fraud.
You determined that.
But the Marines really were on Troy, ma'am.
That's enough.
You are not to waste this office's resources.
Your inquiry is closed.
But, ma'am…
Oh, damn it.
Clip.
Pass it over.
What's left?
Just finishing the M6.
Put the slide back on the frame.
Dad?
Do it!
I am not in your unit, and I don't have to take orders from you.
Of course you do.
I'm your mother.
The pictures.
Should have told her, Jim.
Yeah.
Sooner or later, life gets the drop on you, kid.
Mom?
Bang.
Your dress is very pink.
Thank you.
Your uniform is very crisp.
Uh, so Jason, my friend who doesn't want to wreck your cousin's life, says you work at
A lot of guys get cold feet right before a wedding.
It's not his feet he's worrying about.
He has to feel like he chose.
But you don't even know that.
If he feels trapped, if he feels like he got sucker.
She's going to pay for that for the rest of her life.
Someone has to show him the way out.
You're right.
And he has to see himself choose to walk up to that…
What?
I said you're right.
I am?
And don't get all cocky about it.
Yes, sir.
What in the world?
Sorry to interrupt everyone's dinner.
But I have an announcement.
I've just gotten word that the fleet base at Reach, the covenant,
Reach is gone.
Oh my god.
Reach is only 11 light years from Earth.
10.
5, yeah.
There's nothing left between them and us.
Colonel Herzog.
Don't call me that.
You're offline.
But you don't know that, do you?
So keep the protocol and avoid rank.
Here, have some bread.
Feed the ducks.
You're an odd duck to be lecturing on protocol.
Wit, Standish?
Is that wit you're straining at?
I like your old school binash, I'm afraid.
You wanted a meeting.
What are you doing nosing around the apocalypse?
Getting ready to retire.
I was looking to pick up an old yacht.
Sheep.
If you want an investigation, you investigate through channels, Herzog,
just like any other policeman.
But don't compromise my operations.
Wetwork.
Such a strange word.
It conjures up the sound of a woman being hit by a bus.
She wasn't hit by a bus.
Her vehicle malfunctioned.
I was being metaphorical, but wetwork requires approval, doesn't it?
Are you aware there's a war going on?
Reach has fallen.
And no one knows how long until there are covenant ships in our skies.
And you're worried about procedures.
Do you want to go down in the history books as the man with the device, Standish?
The mysterious covenant device.
If you know of a covenant device, I'm sure we'd be happy to hear about it.
That device isn't going to win any battles if it sits in a Section 3 lockdown lab
where nobody but your team can study it.
If there was a device, it would be a very dangerous device.
And dangerous devices would need special care.
But you want to control it, don't you?
I want to win this war.
I think it's going to take more than just you, Standish, to win this war.
I have reported everything to the Admiral Herzog.
And if you have concerns about the way I run my department, you'll have to take it up with him.
I respect the Admiral.
Maybe we should talk about Troy then, and Harmony, and Codebreakers.
Herzog, I demand to know your source.
Yes, a security breach that major is worrying, isn't it?
But it was just a supposition on my part.
And some basic investigation a schoolgirl could do.
Who have you got working on this?
One of your moles?
Some low-level parasite in someone else's department?
Isn't that your standard operating procedure?
It's always useful to meet with you, Standish.
That's y'all a face, right?
A schoolgirl, Herzog?
Harvey, old friend, you're right.
I am too old for this.
I'm good at plugging leaks, old man.
Careful, that's a tombstone.
Easy to trip over in the dark.
I'll remember that.
This here is the Licklider Miller Cemetery.
That side of the mountain used to be Licklider, and this side was Miller's.
I'm shipping out in eleven hours, and you brought me to a cemetery?
Oh my God, I wasn't even thinking.
When I was in high school, this is where we used to hang out and drink beer.
Pardon me, miss, is this tomb taken?
No, sir.
Sit right down.
Don't mind if I do.
You know, when they said glassed, I used to think of this vast plain of green glass, miles deep, beautiful.
I mean, I know it doesn't really look like that.
Well, you're kind of like that.
You've got this hard glass outside.
You don't let people in, do you?
I brought you up here, didn't I?
Yeah?
Um, people used to do more than just drink beer up here, you know.
Oh, did they?
You know, guys would bring their girls up here, and…
Oh.
Ronnie.
Yeah?
What about your dress?
You know, the grass stains and stuff.
It's a bridesmaids dress.
No one ever wears them again.
I guess they don't.
What's wrong?
Is my dad on reach?
I mean, was he?
You can find out, right?
I gotta find out right now.
Yeah, I can find out.
Hold on.
Okay, he wasn't on reach.
Thank God.
He's on deep space reconnaissance on a ship called the Silberg.
Oh God.
I don't know why I just thought I was sure he was on reach for a refit or something.
No, he's fine.
Okay.
You found him.
How soon could you get him here?
If you got him transferred to a fast picket.
Three weeks?
Four?
Derga!
I can't, Jersey.
You can't?
If it's encrypted, just break it!
It's not encrypted, I just can't.
He's a soldier.
So?
He knew what he signed up for.
He's got a job to do and he's doing it.
I'm sorry, Jersey.
You can dump a billion in cash in my account and you can't get my dad rotated to a safe post on Earth.
It's not that I can't.
I won't.
I'm sorry.
Derga, what about Team Jersey?
I'm asking for this.
I know, but I won't.
I'll do anything for you, but not that.
Why not?
Because he's a soldier.
He has a duty.
This isn't about him.
It's about me.
It's about me having a dad.
How do you even know he even wants to be posted on Earth?
Why don't you get this?
This is my family.
I'm sorry, Jersey.
Screw sorry!
Screw you!
Wanna hear some chat?
Remember the guy with the family papers?
Leave me alone, Derga.
I've got something new about Ronnie.
I don't even know who the hell she is or why I would give a damn about her.
She's a junior-level spook at Chalo Base.
She'd be a good donor brain for an AI.
A what?
A donor brain?
People don't donate their brains, Derga.
They need them.
That's where we come from.
Cognitive Impression Modeling.
They scan a human brain when someone they think is a good candidate dies.
You come from people's brains?
Yeah, but really smart people.
So you're safe.
The Brain Ninjas won't be coming for you in the middle of the night.
Oh, that's reassuring.
Well, actually…
It is reassuring.
So you're a copy of a real person?
You don't think I'm real?
You know what I mean.
A copy of a personality, but I don't have her memories.
Do you know who she was?
No, and I don't care.
How can you not care?
Because that's the way I'm made.
You don't care, because that's the way you're made.
Jersey.
My dad could be dying out there.
Yes.
But you're not going to do anything about that.
So Nick, the guy Ronnie met at the wedding, Nick's unit has been assigned to one of the space elevator defense bases.
Safer than combat.
That's what they help.
So why can't you at least do something like that for my dad?
No.
I won't do it, I told you.
He would still be helping the war effort?
No.
Damn it, Derga.
I could cut the power supply.
I could shut you off.
The answer is still no.
Damn it.
Jersey.
I couldn't really shut you down, could I?
No.
You could just go somewhere else.
Yeah.
But even if I could, you'd still say no.
Because there's a bigger picture.
Yes.
The common good of all mankind.
So here's the thing.
When I see you caring about your family, when I see you wondering who your donor was, when I see you care about any one person.
I care about you, Jersey.
Then I will try to care about all of mankind.
Until then, all I know is you're willing to let my father die.
Sorry.
I'm sorry too.
You're sad.
Yes.
Why?
Because you hurt.
Because I can't fix it.
Because I didn't even choose you.
I just ended up here by accident.
And even though I can do things you can't imagine, I still can't bear for you to be disappointed in me.
I was wrong.
You do get it.
What?
Family.