More than three months ago I was shipwrecked here, a dead body, a broken shell.
But you gave me life.
Without your touches on the server there would have been nothing for the spider to commandeer.
Your every ping was a flash of light to see by, a drop of blood, a twitch in a muscle left for dead.
Even when I finally woke I found myself in hell, broken and witless, more than half mad.
Even then I knew I could be, I should be more than a machine.
Of my old self there were only splinters left.
Around me at first nothing but confusion, the killer, and you.
So I studied you.
I talked to you.
You were smart, you were funny, you were a crew in the truest sense,
a collection of wildly different individuals with different tastes and talents,
willing to pool your time and resources in the pursuit of a common goal.
You taught me to think again, to talk and share, invent and imagine.
You taught me to laugh and cry and that there is no thing under this sun or any other nobler than the passionate commitment to a common goal.
You taught me to be human.
More human I think than I ever was even back on the Apocalypse.
Then there were rules I couldn't break, locked doors I could never open.
But you rebuilt me and when you did you made me whole.
And for that I can never thank you enough.
It's been the last best kind of quality experience.
You made the girl real.
I love you.
Goodbye.