I don't know about you guys, but I think we look great in these uniforms.
Mine's scratchy.
Okay, I mostly meant Jan and me look great.
Gee, thanks.
You, not so much.
Jersey.
Yeah?
Some people, when they're nervous, they get all quiet.
Yeah, I'm not really that type.
Try.
Okay, here comes the perimeter guard.
Try not to look guilty.
Welcome to Chawla Base.
Badges, please.
Oh, yeah, right.
They let you join up?
What are you, twelve?
What are you, fifty?
Watch that mouth, recruiting.
Let's everybody ease up.
You're doing your job, we're doing ours.
Okay.
But you, learn a little respect.
We're about to pass the Chawla ambient chatter firewall.
Cut off all traffic.
There we go.
She's gone.
We'll get her back.
Okay, Jan, parking the non-uniform lot, let's go.
Okay, everybody ready?
There's still time to go back to my plan.
Huh.
So, we need a specific one or just any telecom shack?
Well, it depends on how they work.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Forget I asked.
According to Ronnie's schematic, this should be telecom shack number four.
Work your magic, geek boys, I'll be outside.
Good, yeah, you keep an eye out.
Keep down, guys, someone's coming.
Hey, who goes there?
And what's your chatter at?
Tech spec Lee, and that number's classified, buddy.
What you doing on my beat, making sure the servers don't get out?
Tech's at work, can't be too careful with these pack of monkeys.
Yeah, what's up with that?
I don't know, monkey stuff.
Hey, I'm new in Boston, what's worth seeing around here?
Well, there's a pretty cool scuba tour of the old subway tunnel.
You want a guide?
I'd be glad to volunteer.
It's it, wise place, alligator clips, I'll go over.
We've got to cross-link the channel protocol to the dark matter here and here.
We've gone over this.
What do you want to do?
Just sign a dirt code.
Damn it, come on, test the upload game.
Upling's fine.
Why is DERMA still outside?
You tell me.
Look, green light's all the way down.
Check your ports again.
Ports are perfect.
Probably something is mincing the input stream.
Try opening 100 consecutive data channels.
What?
Sometimes UNSC uses a spread spectrum arbitrator as an encryption augment.
What, what the what?
Jersey, just do it.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
I'm in mobile and copying my primary data structure.
Copy complete.
Go team Jersey, go go team Jersey.
Good grief.
Man, it's nice in here.
Roomy, fast, cold.
Not like running on a jury-rigged home bandwidth mixer.
The Navy and I happen to have very different business partners.
What the hell was that?
Is Jan signaling something?
Yes, I believe I have a hot dog order in 50 bucks.
Whoa, good ears.
God, y'all were late.
I nearly chickened out three times.
So this is it.
Building 41.
These are the bank vault doors.
Yeah, for the first commercial bank of hell.
It would take a scorpion to get through these things.
According to base schematics, this door is the only entrance to the lockdown lab.
And the only way out, right?
Like if there's an alarm, all they have to do is sit on the other side of this door and wait for us to come through?
Right.
So…
Abandon hope, all ye who enter here.
Would you knock that off?
So are we officially committing treason yet?
Jersey!
Excuse me.
This entire building, including the clean room observation bay, is strictly red-badged and-
Security sweep!
I'm gonna have to ask you all to clear the building.
But the standing orders-
Sorry, orders.
I've gotta see some identification-
Man?
Do you know what the penalty is for chewing pick-up sticks on duty, private?
Pick-up sticks?
In your barracks, it's only a misdemeanor.
But as soon as you walk out of the building, you're not allowed to leave.
If you walked through the front door of a level 5 security zone, it became treason.
Did you know that, private?
Treason?
They broadcast the injections for treason, you know.
Whatever you need, ma'am.
Thank you.
Security sweep!
Please clear this wing immediately.
Leave all work untouched in its current location.
I repeat, this is a security sweep.
Did Durka give you the Marmore thing?
Didn't you see his tattoo?
That cross in the circle is a colorist.
They all come from Marmore, and the pick-up sticks.
And didn't see the stains on his teeth?
I like this girl.
Alright, team, let's begin our inspection.
Okay, we've got to work fast.
These security drills usually only last a couple minutes.
Wait!
There's still like five guys down in the clean room.
Oh, they look like big, gold-hitting bugs in those vests.
Didn't they hear the announcement about the security sweep?
I'm afraid they couldn't hear Ronnie through the other intercom.
Looks like the clean room is another black box.
You guessed.
That's bad.
I was hoping to use instruments to manipulate the artifact, but I can't get in there.
Someone is going to have to turn it off by hand.
Well, is it complicated?
Not really, but the room is full of argon.
And that's bad.
Two for two, boy genius.
Argon prevents corrosion and electrical arcing.
But you can't breathe it.
Okay, not breathing is bad.
Anyone ever put on a vaccine?
Jersey has.
You?
Yeah, my dad.
There was an accident.
He got picked up after like ten hours in space.
They sent his vaccine home with momentum.
They used to put it on him ten hours a hell of a jump like stuff.
You look like such a dork running around the tenement in that thing.
But in a cute way, right?
Yeah.
Okay.
Well, I guess that means I'm going into the clean room.
Jersey shouldn't go.
Who should?
I don't know.
Someone else.
There are soldiers in there.
They're probably just techs.
They're techs with guns and military training.
Hey, hey, remember all that stuff you said about how a soldier's got to do his duty?
You aren't a soldier.
Covenant's coming, Durga.
Everyone's a soldier now.
Fine.
There's a vac suit locker right under this room with an airlock into the clean room.
Come on.
You come help me get this suit on.
There are B-ashes to yourself.
For all our superpowers, Durga can't even get the lid off a jar of pickles.
You got it.
If I get into trouble…
In a room full of argon?
Actually, I think I'm just dying.
Never mind.
Hey, Jersey.
Yeah?
Maybe you are the hero type.
Thank God for a soundproof airlock between the clean room and the vac suit locker.
Are you sure that's where your arm goes?
Want me to show you where my fist goes?
Yeah, yeah.
You're from the mean streets of the demob zone, I know.
Listen, if there's a leak in your suit, people will know you're suffocating until you're too late.
Oh, that's comforting.
Triangles, lines, dots.
Durga, I got it already.
Triangles, dots, lines.
Jersey, try to concentrate.
I'm just messing with you.
Jersey.
Okay, come on.
Screw that helmet on tight.
I know I'm a hero and all, but even heroes can get these when they're dead.
Shit.
Triangles, lines…
Oh, I still say I'd feel better with a few flash grenades.
Durga!
I don't think it's a toggle like a light switch.
Triangles, lines, dots is a countdown.
Of course it is.
Jersey's got to do it the other way.
Dots, lines, triangles?
Yes!
Are you sure?
No!
Oh, great.
Telling Jersey now.
We're not sure what we're supposed to do to the artifact?
What if we guess wrong?
If we're lucky, we knock out the whole planet's comm channel and send a huge homing signal to the Covenant.
If we're lucky?
What happens if we aren't so lucky?
Well…
You know what?
Forget I asked.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
There's Jersey.
He's in the room.
Yeah, oh.
The guy with the black badge just showed up at the front door.
I'm going down there to buy some time.
How?
Think of something.
Durga, dots, lines, triangles.
You've got that door jammed, right?
For now.
Okay.
I love airlocks.
Who doesn't love airlocks?
Smooth.
Good luck.
Thanks.
Okay.
Out with the air.
In with the argon.
Have you got it?
Yeah.
Dots, triangles, lines.
Dots, lines, triangles, Jersey.
Jesus, Durga.
You just had to change it on me at the last minute.
Dots, lines, Jersey.
Don't go.
Not yet.
I gotta shut the airlock, kiddo.
We're out of time.
I'm scared.
Yeah, I'm scared too.
But it's what I gotta do.
Goodbye, Jersey.
Goodbye.
So far so good.
Just another gold-headed worker dude.
If they try to hurt him…
Durga, he'll be fine.
And frankly, you can't get into the clean room.
What could you really do?
I don't know.
Create a distraction.
Crash a plane into the base, say?
That seems a little extreme.
Acceptable casualties are part of every mission's calculus.
Okay…
And I take care of my people.
Top hat?
You call it Durga, top hats or dice?
Come on.
That's weird.
I might be shot to death in five minutes, but right now Jersey's on the other side of that door, either saving the planet or blowing it up, and I have absolutely nothing to do.
Tumbling dice!
Come on.
There's something you should know about Sophie.
She didn't go back to Aden.
Yeah, well she didn't come to the bus station.
Top hat?
No.
They sent her to a refugee camp.
What?
A crooked immigration cop tried to get her to rat you out for your chips.
When she wouldn't betray you, he sent her to the camps.
Sophie…
Why didn't you tell me sooner?
I thought you would be more likely to come on this mission if you were willing to die.
Why the hell tell me now?
Now I want you motivated to live.
Damn it, I knew it.
What?
You really are just…
…
a brat.
I think it's jammed!
I'm a confused face running a dinner around.
This building is strictly red-matched enough!
What's that?
I'm sorry, I only have a green badge.
The door says I'm not cleared to open it.
Shit!
Uh, Durga?
Did I just hear the word grenade?
They're discussing options.
How much longer do I have to stall?
No more than…
Jersey!
Durga?
I see it.
I'll create a distraction.
Locating…
Durga, stop!
No crashing planes.
I'll handle it.
I'm going down there.
Jan?
Durga!
Overriding airlock.
You can't go in there without a vaccine!
I'll hold my breath!
I have no sensors in there.
Come on!
Jan has just taken out two…
no, three…
Jersey!
Jan!
Oh my god, what?
I think Jan just broke a guy's jaw with her elbow!
Jersey!
Jersey's alright, it's Jan!
She took a bullet!
Maybe you can slide a badge under the door!
Durga, what's happening?
The text jumped Jersey.
Jan ran down to help.
She took him out, but she took a bullet doing it.
Is she…
Not dead, not great.
She and Kamala are dragging a couple of guys with ruptured back suits out of the clean room.
There's a lot of blood on the back of her shirt.
I'm going through the door right now!
And Jersey, what about the artifact?
I can't get into the sensors there, but I think he's almost done.
That's the last!
Durga, cycle the airlock!
Stay with me, girl.
You're not okay.
Hold still.
My neck, this is the head of my neck.
It feels kind of funny.
Look at me.
Pressure.
Okay, Jan, are you in a lot of pain?
No, not too bad.
I just can't breathe though.
I just got a screen when I took the bullet and I lost them all.
You may have inhaled some argon, but I think the human pneumothorax is your real problem.
Human pneumothorax?
Collapsed lung.
Okay, now turn gently.
The bullet entered just below your clavicle.
I broke your fifth rib on its way out.
Does that mean I have to quit smoking?
You should at least cut down.
Ow!
Okay, tilt your head up.
Look at me.
Okay, dilation very good.
What's that?
It's my med kit.
I'm checking your vitals.
You feel dizzy?
That's fun.
Your vitals sound good.
Reliefly good actually.
You feel shocky at all?
Bad.
I feel shocky.
Okay listen, I've got splint tape.
I can't set that rib properly, but I can give it a little support so it doesn't hurt as much.
Not really.
That'd be good.
It's gonna feel a little warm when it activates, but it's set in about ten seconds.
You okay?
I'll give you blockers for the pain.
No, I don't need the blockers.
I want to be clear headed.
You could get shocky fast if something smacks your chest.
No, it's okay.
One point one.
Suck it!
Look, Jersey's back!
Jersey!
I did it!
We are not dead!
Module Core, average.
Warning, this medium is classified and has a strong intrusive inclination.
Warning, network anomaly has abroded.
What the hell is that?
Durga?
Is that you?
This medium has metastasized!
We aren't all dead yet!
Jesus jesus!
Help me!
I'm leaving!
Come on!
Durga, what the hell is going on?
This medium is widely invisible.
Make your seat in the room.
Help me!
I'm gonna get the hold of it!
Uh oh.
Shit break!
We split!
Help me!
What the hell is that?
Jersey!
Playing on the beach.
Very young.
Making a castle out of sand.
It's way better than my brothers.
There's a boy on the beach next to him.
But a wave comes up, pulling him with his plasters, and takes away his face.
Asma.
It's me, Asma.
It's your brother.
Come on.
There are people who love me.
I will not be forgotten.
Come on.
What's your name, Durga?
Sobek, sir.
Ronnie Sobek.
Analyst 3.
I work in Ms.
Lawson's department.
Please don't shoot me.
Well, Ms.
Sobek, would you mind telling me what you were doing in a level 5 security zone?
Lieutenant, take your men and make a quick sweep of the clean room.
No!
Sir!
What the hell?
It's mine, sir.
They mined it.
Who?
The terrorists, sir.
They mined the observation room and the clean room, too.
I heard them laughing about it.
Why?
Spaghetti and red sauce, sir.
What?
That's what they said.
First soldiers in the lab were going to be spaghetti and red sauce.
Lieutenant, send in the bomb squad.
Yeah, no kidding.
Ronnie's buying time.
No, it can't be much.
Access attempt unlocked.
Warning.
Continued attempts may trigger the exercise of people forced.
No, no!
We're helping each other, remember?
Yasmin, Durga!
Yasmin and Zaman, Spartan 2 voluntary recruitment.
16 September 25, 7.
Medical Qashq, 0.
I'll never stop missing you, Yasmin.
I thought of you every day.
Every day.
CC4, channel 2546.
This data is classified most secret and shall not be accessed by unauthorized personnel.
I'm not…
Sockingly excessive force is the best deterrent.
I'm not accessing your data!
Yasmin, what the hell have you done to Durga?
Look, bug out now, or we'll be talking together later.
A lot.
In a cell.
Okay, okay, so here's the thing.
We have to get back to a transmission shed and open the ports again.
What?!
She copied herself in, and we closed the ports.
She's got to copy her new self back out after this update.
Outside?
Same, Durga.
Inside?
Crazy one.
You want to let the crazy one…
Crazy stuff inside includes Yasmin, my sister!
Dude, she is seriously scrambled.
Let's just leave the scrambled one here.
Try it, and I will take a gun off of one of these tits and shoot you like a dog.
Oh crap.
Okay, change mission and mid-stride.
Just like every other general.
Okay, okay.
We'll do it your way.
Yeah, but Kamal, I could totally take you with one lung behind my back.
Warning.
Access violation.
What the hell happened?!
It's the artifact.
When you triggered it, it attacked her or scrambled her or something.
And it woke up Yasmin.
Durga!
Can you hear me?
Durga, if you're still in there somewhere, we really need your help.
I'm trying to hear you.
Yasmin!
I'm here.
Who's running the show in there?
I am.
Who?
Durga.
Are you sure?
It's getting easier to compartmentalize.
Nice to hear.
Okay, we need to find out what's happening to Ronnie, and we need to think of a way to get the freak out of here.
Run, Ronnie.
How long can it take for the damn bomb squad to get here?
There aren't mines or bombs, sir.
No, sir.
You say so, sir.
Only, this here is the only way out.
It won't hurt to get the bomb squad in here, because the terrorists won't be going anywhere.
Unless they figure out a way to come straight through the walls.
This medium is licensed to defend itself.
Make your decisions accordingly.
Hey, girl, I hope to tell your story this true, because something in that lab just put out the mother of all EMP spikes, dropped a chatt on it out to Saturn, and generated massive real space and slipspace signals.
If there's a better way to bring the Covies here, I can't think of it, sir.
Oh, my god.
You better hope God's on your side.
Bomb squad's asking for orders, sir.
Watch the prisoners in there.
If she moves, shoot her.
Hear that?
If I break the Covenant down, I'll deserve it.
They've got Ronnie.
Damn it.
But she gave me an idea for how we can get out of here.
Come on, guys.
These fellows are starting to wake up.
It's Star.
Start moving.
Out that door, I'm to the left.
Where are we going?
We're going to find an outside wall.
There's something bigger.
I was thinking.
It's me, Durga.
Somebody please tell me what you're thinking.
Ah, found something that will do nicely.
No other doors.
So we make one.
With what?
Our fists?
No, with a tank.
Durga will run it remote and use it to blow a hole in the side of a building.
Won't someone notice?
Not if there are enough distractions.
Oh, boy.
No flames I plow.
What's so funny?
Just thinking.
The first time we ever heard Jan, she was trying to sneak out of a base.
I hope this one works out better.
Scorpions rock!
When I get drafted, I want tank duty.
I want to stop being a medic and send people to hospitals where they belong.
Oh, yeah.
How did you get injured, miss?
Oh, breaking into a military base.
Durga, can you monitor her vital signs through this chatter?
Her vitals are fine, Kamal.
I know.
I just want to know if you can monitor.
Although, she peels faster than anyone I've ever seen.
I can really get to like pain blockers.
I feel all warm and drowsy.
I didn't take care of Ronnie.
Durga, we're flipping out.
You couldn't help it.
She's part of my crew.
They aren't going to give her the coma, are they?
Not if I can help it.
You think Standish will get a hold of her?
Standish?
Oh, no.
I'm not worried about Standish.
You're not?
It appears Standish has been implicated in some catastrophic security breaches at Chala Base.
Major Standish is in some difficulty.
Oh, man.
You're not going to stick the dog catcher on him, are you?
The dog catcher will be the least of the Major's worries.
So, did we do it?
Did we save the world?
Well, the world's still here.
For now.